servint.net 2013-06-06

# Privacy Policy and Copyright Notice | ServInt | www.servint.net

### ServInt Privacy and Copyright Notices

### 1\. Privacy Policy

#### Effective: 05-02-2011

The ServInt Corporation (ServInt, we, us or our) is concerned about the privacy of information provided to us and to third parties with whom we do business. Because everyone's definition of privacy is different, it is important that you review this policy to learn what we consider to be private information, and each of our rights and responsibilities towards this information. This privacy policy is part of your contract with us, or, if you do not have a contract, it governs information you provide to us. Terms that are not defined in this policy are defined in your contract with us.

It is also important that you review this policy from time to time, particularly if your business changes, or if you begin to send us new types of information. It is our goal to limit the number of changes we make to this policy. If we do make a change, we will notify you through your customer portal. Other than in an emergency, we will give you thirty days prior notice of any change, and the new policy will be effective on the thirty-first day of our notice. If such a change materially interferes with your ability to use the Services in the manner you used them prior to the change, and such a use was not previously prohibited by law or our policies, you may terminate the Services you purchase from us with no termination charge. 

ServInt has qualified for the European Unions Safe Harbor framework for the transmission and processing of personally identifiable information from the EU to the US. This framework is administered by the U.S. Department of Commerce. We have self-certified to the Department of Commerce that we are in compliance with this framework. General questions about this policy, or information that is not covered by the framework, should be directed to our Chief Technology Officer.

It is important for you to know that all information we collect may be provided to law enforcement officials, government entities or pursuant to civil litigation demands. We will provide you with written notice of such a request through your portal except in the following circumstances: we are required not to by law, or we receive a request from a law enforcement agency not to do so. Because laws and regulations differ, we do not guarantee that information we provide to law enforcement, regulatory and government entities will be kept confidential.

**What data does ServInt collect?**

There are three types of data that we collect: data that is required by us to provide Services to you; data that is automatically collected by us; and data you voluntarily provide to us. 

We collect the following personal information from you:

  * Contact Information. This is information you are required to provide to us to enable us to contact you. Examples of contact information may include name, email address, mailing address, telephone number and facsimile information. Contact information may identify you personally.
  * Billing Information. This is information you are required to provide to us to enable us to be paid for the Services, or for a third party to provide services through us to you. Examples of billing information may include credit card number, bank information, PayPal id, billing address, billing contact name, telephone numbers and email address. Billing information may identify you personally.
  * Password Information. This is information that allows you to access the Services, technical support, our ticketing system and any third party services provided through us. Examples of password information may include user id, account number and password. Password information does not identify you personally, but when associated with other information, it may.
  * Technical Information. This is information that allows us to configure the Services so that they are more easily provided to you. Examples of technical information may include your IP address, browser type, referring/exit pages, operating system, and affiliate id. Technical information does not identify you personally, but when associated with other information, it may.
  * Voluntary Information. This is information you choose to provide to us and that is not necessary for the operation of the Services. Examples of voluntary information include submissions to our knowledgebase, your endorsements of us and your connections to us in social networks. It is your decision whether you include information that identifies you personally when you provide voluntary information to us.

**How does ServInt use the data it collects?**

We will use contact information as follows:

  * To provide the Services to you;
  * To notify members of our affiliate program that you have contacted us, or purchased Services from us, and pay them for this; 
  * To contact you about the Services;
  * To contact you about our business and new products and services we offer;
  * To allow third parties to provide their services through us to you; and
  * To law enforcement, regulatory and government entities to whom we believe we are required to provide it by law.

We do not make this information public except as provided above. However, it is possible that this information may become public. For example, contact information may be provided to a domain name registrar who publishes that information in a who-is register. If you were referred to us by a member of our affiliate program, they may receive certain contact information from us. This information allows them to verify that they are being accurately paid for their referrals. We require them to keep this information confidential, but cannot be responsible if they breach our contract.

We will use billing information as follows:

  * To provide the Services to you;
  * To bill you, or have third party services bill you, for the Services;
  * To allow third parties to provide their services through us to you; and
  * To law enforcement, regulatory and government entities to whom we believe we are required to provide it by law.

We require third parties to whom we provide billing information to keep this information confidential, but cannot be responsible if they breach our contract. 

We will use password information as follows:

  * To provide the Services to you;
  * To allow third parties to provide their services through us to you; and
  * To law enforcement, regulatory and government entities to whom we believe we are required to provide it by law.

We require third parties to whom we provide password information to keep this information confidential, but cannot be responsible if they breach our contract. 

We will use technical information as follows:

  * To provide the Services to you;
  * To allow third parties to provide their services through us to you; 
  * To troubleshoot the Services, and allow third parties to assist us in doing so; and
  * To law enforcement, regulatory and government entities to whom we believe we are required to provide it by law.

We require third parties to whom we provide technical information to keep this information confidential, but cannot be responsible if they breach our contract.

We will use voluntary information as follows:

  * To enhance our services;
  * To help third parties use our services; and
  * In our advertising.

You may voluntarily connect with us on many different social networking platforms. Their privacy policies, not this privacy policy, govern our use of that data. We may use social networking data to the fullest extent permitted by the privacy policies of the provider.

**Will you sell data?**

Contact information, billing information, password information and technical information will only be sold in conjunction with the sale of all or a portion of our business. 

**Can I opt out?**

You may opt out of receiving information about our business, new products, and the services we offer. Simply uncheck the mailing list option under the contact information section in your customer portal. Once you provide voluntary information to us, you may not opt out of its use.

**How do I change the information you collect?**

To change any of the information set out in this policy, other than voluntary information, you need to log into your customer portal and change or modify it. For information we control, these changes will be immediate. However, it may take some time for third parties to change your information. This is particularly true of certain types of contact information and technical information. For example, if you change your contact information, it may take several days for a domain name registrar to make those changes. You should never assume that any changes to that type of information will be immediate. Once you provide voluntary information to us, you may not change it.

**Information tracking programs**

Our site uses information tracking programs. These programs may be cookies, single-pixel gifs (web beacons) or other technology that provides us with information about your activities on our site and the internet in general. Information tracking programs do things like keep track of your preferences and profile information so that you do not have to enter that information each time you visit our site (Preferences), or to modify our site so that it presents information to you that we believe you will find helpful. These programs may also collect usage and volume statistical information. Other than Preferences, no personally identifiable information is collected by us. We do not provide the Preferences to third parties.

If you do not want your Preferences stored on your computer, you can deselect this option when you are asked for this information. If you wish to change the Preferences after you chose to have them stored, you may log into your customer portal and change them. For information collected other than the Preferences, it is your obligation to configure your browser so that this information is not collected.

**How do you secure this information?**

When you provide us with information covered by this policy it is protected by encrypted SSL. The information is stored on secured servers configured to allow only authorized access. This information is encrypted when required by the laws that generally apply to our industry or as required by our vendors.

No information transmitted on the internet, nor stored on servers, is 100% secure. The methods set out above are industry standard security measures. Nevertheless, dishonest people exist, software and hardware can malfunction and people make mistakes. As a result, we cannot guarantee that any information covered by this policy will be absolutely secure.

**Who certified your Safe Harbor statement?**

Our COO, and we annually certify our continued compliance with the framework directly to the U.S. Department of Commerce.

**I have more questions. Who do I contact?**

If you are not a customer, please email us at: [sales@servint.com](mailto:sales@servint.com).

If you are a current customer, the fastest way for you to contact us about this policy is to open a support ticket through your customer portal. If you would rather contact us by email, you may email us at [admin@servint.com](mailto:admin@servint.com).

### 2\. Copyright

All content is Copyright 1995-2011 The ServInt Corporation. All rights reserved.

Copyright in this document is owned by ServInt. Any person is hereby authorized to view, copy, print and distribute documents found on this Web site (www.servint.net) provided that:

  1. Documents and images are used for informational purposes only.
  2. Documents and images are not used for commercial purposes.
  3. Documents, images or portions thereof must include this copyright notice.

Products, technologies and processes described in this website (www.servint.net) may be subject to ServInt’s intellectual property rights and are not licensed hereunder.

### 3\. Restricted Rights

Use, duplication, or disclosure by the United States Government is subject to the restrictions set forth in DFARS 252.227-7013 (c)(l)(ii) and FAR 52.227-19.

### 4\. Trademarks/Servicemarks

ServInt is a registered trademark of The ServInt Corporation. “Relax. Your server is up and running.”, “A different kind of ISP”, “The ServInt Source”, “Essential VPS”, “Signature VPS”, “Ultimate VPS”, “SuperVPS” and “VPSpro” are trademarks of ServInt. All other product names mentioned herein are the trademarks of their respective owners.

THIS WEBSITE AND INFORMATION WITHIN IS PROVIDED “AS IS” WITHOUT WARRANTY OF ANY KIND, EITHER EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY, FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE, OR NON-INFRINGEMENT. THIS WEB SITE COULD INCLUDE TECHNICAL INACCURACIES OR TYPOGRAPHICAL ERRORS. CHANGES ARE PERIODICALLY MADE TO THE INFORMATION HEREIN; THESE CHANGES WILL BE INCORPORATED IN NEW EDITIONS OF THE WEBSITE SERVINT MAY MAKE IMPROVEMENTS AND/OR CHANGES IN THE PRODUCT(S) AND/OR THE PROGRAM(S) DESCRIBED IN THIS PUBLICATION AT ANY TIME.

### 5\. Contacting ServInt

For further information on trademark matters contact ServInt at 800-5-SERVINT (800-573-7846).

Any questions or bug reports regarding this service should go to: [sales@servint.net](mailto:sales@servint.net).
